SVETLANA VAZ

+1(213) 422-6330 or +1(213) 342-1679 http://linkedin.com/in/svetvaz Sunnyvale, CA 94085 svetvaz@gmail.com

Jan 2014 - Present

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over 9 years of comprehensive server side development experience in the industry using Java, Javascript, Python, Node.js, D3.js, express, web sockets and other server programming tools. Highly interested in automating development processes, machine learning, NLP and mobile application development

CORE EXPERTISE

- Design Patterns
 Client Server and Web architecture frameworks
 Server Side Development
- Agile, Scrum • Data Structures & Algorithms

INTERESTS

• Machine Learning • Analytics Software • Natural Language Processing

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dropthought Inc. Santa Clara, California **Full Stack Engineer**

- Developed an automated API testing suite with a web interface
 - ✓ Built a robust testing suite to test every API call using Frisby, js, Jasmine, Node, js, Express, Html 5, CSS and Javascript
- Developed a sentiment based language analysis web app using Natural Language Processing
 - ✓ Generated unigrams, bigrams and trigrams of the input feed using NLTK
 - ✓ Created word cloud using d3.js, Node.js and Express
- Developed the server side for the core instant feedback capturing product for executive briefing centers and events
 - ✓ Wrote the Node is layer to communicate between the API and the front end built using Angular is
 - ✓ Introduced a security layer to encrypt data both at the front end and on the transport layer
- Integrated an analytics software tool 'Tableau' into Dropthought
 - ✓ Setup a MySql connection for automated data updates to tableau
 - ✓ Embedded tableau results onto a dashboard for easy visualization of feedback analysis
 - ✓ Added trusted authentication of requests to the tableau server

Heal the Bay May 2012 - Dec 2013 Santa Monica, California Force.com Developer

- Followed agile(scrum) methodology throughout the project
 - ✓ Conducted detailed interviews with each of the stake holders to gather requirements
 - ✓ Analyzed and categorized requirements as per business
 - ✓ Created High level design for the new structure
- Redesigned the salesforce database, customized to meet the clients requirements

✓ Developed apex triggers, classes and workflows from scratch

Barclays Bank PLC, Credit Cards

Aug 2010-Sep 2011

Pune, India

Solution Architect

- Recommended future state business requirements, processes, technologies, applications and information systems to create the 'to-be' target from an 'as-is' baseline
 - ✓ Performed gap analysis and cost vs. effort estimation
- Defined & validated technical requirements & architecture quality attributes and accordingly recommended technical solutions for application integration
 - ✓ Provided high level solution for client-server and N-tier critical applications

Swisscom IT Services Finance AG

Aug 2007 - Jul 2010

Zurich, Switzerland

Senior Software Engineer

- Developed features for a securities lending product to service borrowing and lending, repo, synthetic finance, collateral management and risk management
 - ✓ Analyzed & estimated story points for user stories using poker estimation
 - ✓ Developed user stories using Core & Advanced Java
 - ✓ Wrote unit tests using JUnit

Fidelity Investments

Aug 2006 - May 2007

Tonbridge, United Kingdom

Java Developer

- Functional Verification Testing & Bug Fixes on a middleware system that validates mutual fund applications
 - ✓ Performed root cause analysis, report and bug fixes
 - ✓ Resolved most of the critical issues within a span of 2 hours max

Commonwealth Bank Of Australia

Apr 2006 - Jun 2006

Sydney, Australia

Java Developer

- Maintenance of a Business forex service that facilitated transactions for import, export, foreign currency borrowings, foreign currency investments, profit & interest repatriation
 - ✓ Design of use cases and Use case diagrams using Rational Rose
 - ✓ System Testing and Bug Fixes

JPMorgan, London

Apr 2004 - Mar 2006

Pune, India

Java Developer

- Maintenance of a Third Party Reference Database and consequent development of reports to be sent to JPM Message Express (MX) using JSP, Servlets, EJB, IBM WSAD, IBM Websphere, MQSeries and Oracle
 - ✓ Managed bug fixes and development of new requirements

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Technology	Proficient	Competent
Programming Languages	Java, Javascript, SQL, Force.com, Python, R	Obj-C, IAT _E X
Operating Systems	Linux, Unix, OS-X	Windows
Platforms & Frameworks	iOS (Xcode), Express.io, Node.js, NLTK	Spring, Hadoop
Testing	JUnit, Frisby.js, Jasmine	PyUnit
Version Control	Git, Subversion	CVS
Tools & Utilities	Eclipse, Tableau, RStudio, Omnigraffle, Sublime	QFTest, Collabnet, TOAD
Databases	MySQL, SQLite, Oracle	DB2
CRM	Salesforce	

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Certificate, Computer Programming

University of California (Extension), Santa Cruz, CA GPA: 4.0 Aug 2014

Project - Forecasting the severity of Seasonal Influenza using Supervised Machine Learning

Post Graduate Award, Mobile Application Development

University of California (Extension), Santa Cruz, CA GPA: 4.0 Aug 2014

Project - Loyalty Rewards Program for a Point of Sales System Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

PCCE, Goa, India 1st class Distinction with honors Aug 2003 (graduated)

REFERENCES

References provided upon request. (Online references available at LinkedIn).